# EDAR CHENG

#### SUMMARY

Three years of software development work experience, proficient in C++ and Python programming languages, as well as data operations with MySQL. Especially, my experience is in developing distributed storage systems in private clouding platforms, SDKs in big data platforms, compilers, and industrial (desktop) software.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, C, C++, JavaScript, SQL, Redis, Shell

Developer Tools: VS Code, Visual Studio, VIM

Technologies/Frameworks: Linux, Git, Django, Qt, FLask, Scarpy, CEPH, Dokcer, Kubernetes

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Runjian 🗹

2023.02 - Present

Beijing, China

EBConverter As a software development engineer in the DEA software team, using C++ and Qt to complete tasks which responsible for implementing drawing(XML) conversion functions to ensure that data is accurately transmitted between different

JD.com 🕜

2021.10 - 2022.08

Software Engineer

Software Engineer

Beijing, China

- SQL Parser SQL Parser is a SDK for Generate AST by parsing the SQL input by the user through Lexer and parser, and then perform code generation to generate the corresponding secure computing Python API code (ANTLR, Pyspark), and the parsing ability is improved by 50%.
- developed custom user login, code detection, custom kernel, and other functions, which enable user to login platform and use jupyter kernel delopled by our team(Jupyter, Python, Kubernetes, Docker).
- File Service File Service is a microservice, my role is to developed user data storage, query, and other related functions (Flask, Pandas) which supports access to file list of folders from the file system, HDFS, and Amazon S3 interfaces, creating folders, obtaining CSV and ORC format headers, obtaining metadatas. An average increase of 30% in final response speed.

## Institute of Information Engineering, Chinese Academy of Sciences Software Engineer

Beijing, China

- Security Authorization Management System Optimized the user interface and implemented the backend functions (C++, QT, socket) of the security and security authorization management system of the virtualization platform, reducing the time to manage access by 40% through automation.
- Distributed Storage System My role is to designed and implemented a distributed storage system, mainly implementing user management, uploading and downloading files, file collection and sharing, user history viewing, and other functions (CEPH, Linux, Django, Boto3, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python).
- Storage Cluster Monitoring Module Storage cluster monitoring module development and document online browsing function implementation (Flask, JavaScript, Python).

## Yuexin Technology 🗹 Software Engineer Intern

2019.06 - 2019.12

Beijing, China

- Data warehouse extraction, scheduling, processing, cleaning, and analysis of hundreds of millions of data levels.
- Use ETL tools to write scripts and SQL to process data (Kettle, JavaScript).
- Develop data crawlers for enterprise industrial and commercial data, which make more that 200Million lines data became updated. (Python, Scrapy, XPath).

#### Open Source Projects and Works

# University Information Retrieval System

2019.12 - present

- Built and deployed a web system .
- This system regularly captures data of 1500 universities from other websites and displays the data on the page (scrapy, HTML, CSS, JavaScript).
- User can register, log on, activate, view history, and collect satisfactory institutions (Redis, Celery).
- Retrieve university information (MySQL, Amap API, Whoosh, Haystack) through keywords, longitude, latitude, and ranking.

# Chinese Language Sssessment System C | Django, JavaScript, Xunfei API

2020.07 - 2020.10

- Built a web system that can input English-generated corresponding audio files and play online, and display the corresponding audio map.
- Through this system, Chinese can be entered online and scores can be given in real-time.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Guangdong Baiyun University

2016.09 - 2020.07

Bachelor's in Information Management and Information System

Guangzhou, China

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

• Machine Learning - Coursera